BHARATH G

FRONTEND DEVELOPER

MY PORTFOLIO: HTTPS://BHARATHPORTFOLIO9.NETLIFY.APP/

CONTACT



+91 9080945108

bharathkarnan199@gmail.com

https://www.linkedin.com/in/b harath-g/

TECHNOLOGIES/TOOLS

Frontend Frameworks

Javscript and libraries like ES5.ES6. React JS. Redux. Material-ui, Jest, jQuery and **Typescript**

CSS Preprocessor

React Bootstrap, LESS, SCSS and worked with UI framework Bootstrap4 with HTML5 and CSS3 flavours

Accessibility

Web-Accessibility(WCAG 2.0)

Methodology

Agile, Waterfall

Version Control

GIT, Bitbucket

AWARDS

Honored with the "AMBER and CORAL Award" for ensuring the on-time and efficient delivery of multiple projects with zero escalations.

Consistently recognized by my Lead and colleagues for exceptional contributions and teamwork.

PROFILE

I am a technically proficient UI developer with over 3 years of experience in frontend technologies and design. I am highly adaptable and quick to learn new skills, with a strong passion for creating responsive and visually engaging websites.

EXPERIENCES

DESIGNATION - TECHNICAL LEAD

EY | SEP 2024 TO PRESENT

Responsible Al Toolkit (Sep 2024 - Present)

- Independently developed dynamic, user-friendly dashboards for different users.
- Incorporated various chart types to effectively visualize detection data for end-users.
- Implemented advanced questionnaire and filtering functionalities to enhance dashboard interactivity.
- Integrated jsPDF to enable PDF generation for detailed detection reports.
- Optimized dashboard performance, reducing load times and enhancing overall application efficiency.

Technologies Used- React JS, Redux, Material UI SASS, Highcharts

DESIGNATION - SOFTWARE ENGINEER (REACT JS)

Cognizant Technology Solutions | AUG 2021 TO SEP 2024

ACE - SUPPLY CHAIN PORTFOLIO - (Retail) (Aug 2021 - Sep 2024)

ARMA Services

- Developed a React is application for ARMA services which is a e-commerce platform used for buying a retail products.
- Designed and developed various functionality for ARMA app which includes (Add To Cart, Shopping Cart, Swiper, Checkout Order for products).
- Effectively used React Storybook for creating a reusable components.

SOFT SKILLS

Teamwork
Analytical
Methodical
Self motivated

EDUCATION

2017-2021- B.E Electronics and Communication Engineering, KPR Institute of Engineering and Technology.

2016-2017 - 12th, AVP Trust Matric Hr Sec School.

LANGUAGES

English Tamil

- Independently converted all JavaScript files to TypeScript files.
- Utilized micro frontend feature for developing the retail websites.
- Used REST API's for handling the data in the frontend with the help of Redux library.
- Handled Adobe and Google analytics.
- Effectively used JEST for writing a generic test cases
- Validated multiple websites and fixed the accessibility issues based on WCAG 2.0 Guidelines.

Technologies Used- Javascript, React JS, Redux, Typescript, Jest, SASS, jQuery, Bootstrap

PERSONAL PROJECTS

Real Chat App

• Developed Real Chat web application using react js and firebase in a responsive manner.

Link: https://bhrealchatapp2023.netlify.app/

Technologies used - React JS, Tailwind, Firebase

BhPizzaCastle

 Developed PizzaCastle website with Sign Up, Login Functionality, Add to Cart, Wishlist in a responsive manner.

Link: https://bhpizzacastle.netlify.app/login

Technologies used - React JS, Firebase

CERTIFICATIONS

- Certified with Completion of "Build Responsive Real world websites with HTML5 and CSS3" from UDEMY.
- Certified with Completion of "Javascript Basics for Beginners" from UDEMY.
- English Proficiency-B2 Upper Intermediate
 -British Council.
- Certified with Completion of "The Complete jQuery course: From Beginner To Advanced".